Guide to the Erasmus Hall Records 1325–1989 (bulk circa 1775–1975) MS 201
New-York Historical Society
- "Archives of Erasmus Hall High School"
  - Flatbush Reformed Dutch Church
    - [Stained glass windows], circa 1889 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Flatbush Reformed Dutch Church)
      Report by Dr. John L. Zabriskie, chairman of the committee appointed to ascertain the cost of stained glass windows for the church, and recommending the Tiffany Glass Company for the work. n.d., but probably 1889. Two-leaf manuscript in the writing of Dr. John L. Zabriskie.
  - Flatbush Reformed Dutch Church—Sabbath School
    - "The Melodeon," published for the benefit of the Infant Department of the Reformed Dutch Church Sabbath-School. Flatbush, L. I.," v. 1, no. 1., 1865 February 22 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Flatbush Reformed Dutch Church)
      Contains valuable account of the appearance of the houses along Flatbush Avenue, starting at the southern end of town, in 1865.
  - Flatbush Short Stories
    - "Flatbush Short Stories", 1923–1926 (Offsite-box RC-6b, Folder Flatbush Short Stories)
  - Flatbush-Tompkins Congregational Church
    - "Apple Blossoms in a Churchyard Move Brooklyn Pastor to Poetry," New York Times, 1956 May 15 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Churches)
  - Flatlands Reformed Church
    - "Brooklyn Protestantism 300 Years Old Tomorrow," New York Herald Tribune, 1954 February 8 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Churches)
      Deals with Flatlands Reformed Church (illustration).
  - Flying Dutchman
    - The Flying Dutchman. Published by the Senior Class of Erasmus Hall High School, Brooklyn, June, Nineteen Hundred and One, 1901 (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Flying Dutchman)
      240 p.
  - Flying Dutchman II
    - The Flying Dutchman II. An Exposition of a New York City High School with Its Activities. Published by the Students of Erasmus Hall High School Under the Auspices of the Monday Club, Borough of Brooklyn, 1911 April (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Flying Dutchman II)
      308 p.
    - Flying Dutchman II [original artwork], circa 1911 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Correspondence regarding various EHHS publications | Original artwork for Flying Dutchman II)
  - Flying Dutchman III
    - The Flying Dutchman III. Published by the General Organization of Erasmus Hall High School, 1920 June (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Flying Dutchman III)
      196 p.
  - Forest Leaf
    - "The Forest Leaf," published for the benefit of the festival in aid of the soldiers' orphans; Flatbush, L. I., 1865 July 6 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder "The Forest Leaf")
      Two-page newspaper to muster support for this fundraising affair. Includes two legends of old Flatbush, "The Dominie's Ride" and "Legend of Pope's Lane." The latter was obviously the source for John J. Snyder's tale of Fiddler Joe in Tales of Old Flatbush (1945).
  - Glass negatives
    - "Old Glass negatives Mr. Silver", circa 1912–1931, undated (Box RC-19a, Enclosure 1)
      • Litchfield mansion, Prospect Park
      • "Unveiling of Plaque" [attached to base of Erasmus statue]
      • No. 746 Date Nov/28 Photo by JM View of Old Building
      • Dr. Low and Miss Latham looking at G.O. posters, 1928
      • Office of principal J. Herbert Low, showing old fireplace
      • Brass plaque on rear of Erasmus statue
      • Brass plaque on front of statue of Erasmus on campus, 1931
      • [unidentified] [Men working on trolley tracks]
      • No. 188. Room 304
      • No. 734 Date: Nov/28 Photo by JM view of quadrangle from balcony
      • No. 742 Date: Nov/28 Photo by JM View of Quad
      • Subway construction, Prospect Park, 192[9?]
      • [Students on campus]
      • No. 1153; Date 5/6/29; Activity: Gardening; Photo by Bert Sternfield; Place: Front Campus; Dr. King's gardeners (picked from the boys gym class) digging up the campus prior to planting for the spring [plus 2 other neg's. of work on campus]
      • Home Ec. Class
      • [Young children on steps] (lantern slide)
      • [Erasmus pupils (?) behind Flatbush District School No. 1] (lantern slide)
      • [Students in costume for pageant (1912?)]
      • [Erasmus statue dedication? (1931?)]
      • [Students in costume behind Erasmus Hall Academy building?]
      • [Back Campus. Bedford Ave. Cottages used for Classrooms] (see print in enclosure 4)
    - "Glass Plate Negatives", 1901–1906, undated (Box RC-19a, Enclosure 2)
      • "Girl's Basketball, 1906"
      • "Girl's Basketball, Nov. 10, '03"
      • "Miss Brown; Crespi; Iffla; Wilcox; Billings; Bradley; Hillman; Vacarrazza"
      • "Original Basketball Team EHHS"
      • "Boys' Glee Club, 1901"
      • "Girls' Mandolin Club, 1906"
      • [Girls on horseback]
      • [Football Team]
      • [Main hall, EHHS, showing oil portrait of Dr. Gunnison]
      • [Girls' LaCrosse Team]
      • [Excellent view of Church Ave. wing]
      • [Boys swimming, probably Prospect Park Lake]
      • [Picnic?]
      • [Class of 1901]
      • [Boy's Baseball Team]
      • "Baseball Team, '06"
      • [Baseball Team]
      • [Girls' Basketball Team, 1904]
      • [Greek club?]
      • [Dr. Walter B. Gunnison at his desk]
      • [Election Posters on EHHS Campus]
      • [Girls on Horseback]
      • [unidentified]
    - Glass negatives, 1891–1918, undated (Box RC-19a, Enclosure 3)
      • [Students, June '91]
      • [Students]
      • [Orchestra, c. 1901] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Orchestra, c. 1901]
      • [Academy Building during election] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Back campus Bedford Ave. Cottages used for classrooms] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Faculty outing] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Dr. Gunnison, Miss Turner, 1911] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Dr. Gunnison, Miss Turner, students] (see print in enclosure 4)
      • [Football team]
      • [Girls' Basketball Team, 1901]
      • [Girls' Basketball, 1918]
      • [Girls' Tennis]
      • [Boys' Baseball Team]
      • [Boys' Basketball Team, 1907]
    - 8 x 10 prints, circa 1901–1911, undated (Box RC-19a, Enclosure 4)
      • Faculty outing
      • Back campus Bedford Ave. Cottages used for classrooms
      • Dr. Gunnison, Miss Turner, 1911
      • Dr. Gunnison, Miss Turner, Students
      • [Orchestra]
      • Academy Building during election
      • Academy Building
  - Good Neighbor
    - "The Good Neighbor," published by the Pan-American Club of Erasmus Hall High School, vol. 2, edition 1, 1938 June (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Pan American Club Publications)
  - Grade IV Magazine, Grade VI Magazine
    - "Grade IV Magazine," published by the Class of 1940. Vol. 1, no. 2, 1938 June (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder EHHS—Misc. Publications)
    - "Grade VI Magazine," published by the Class of 1940. Vol. 3, no. 1 [2 copies], 1939 Spring (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder EHHS—Misc. Publications)
  - Gunn, Alexander
    - Gunn, Alexander. Memoirs of the Rev. John H. Livingston... (New York: William A. Mercein), 1829, 1856 (Offsite-box RC-11, Folder Gunn. Memoirs of Rev. John H. Livingston)
      Two editions (1829 and 1856).
  - Gunnison, Almon, D.D., LL.D.
    - [Publications regarding Dr. Almon Gunnison], 1914 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Dr. Almon Gunnison)
      Two publications regarding Dr. Almon Gunnison, brother of Walter Balfour Gunnison of EHHS, and pastor of All Souls Universalist Church:
      • The Laurentian. Canton, N.Y.: St. Lawrence University, v. 27, no. 8 (Nov. 1914). Dedicated to Dr. Almon Gunnison.
      • Record and Tribute to Dr. Almon Gunnison, 1899–1914.
  - Gunnison, Walter Balfour (EHHS principal, 1896–1916)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, programs, etc., 1905–1919 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Walter Balfour Gunnison (folder 1))
      • Directions for the funeral of Dr. Gunnison held at All Souls Universalist Church, Dec. 21, 1916. The arrangements were made by EHHS, and the whole faculty and selected students attended.
      • Mimeograph copies of songs apparently sung at a testimonial dinner for Dr. Gunnison. The words were to be sung to such popular tunes as "There is a Tavern in the Town," "Solomon Levi," etc.
      • Obituary from New York Times, Dec. --, 1916.
      • Program of Seventh Annual Dinner of EHHS Faculty, Feb. 25, 1905, at which time the portrait of Dr. Gunnison was unveiled (copy appears on cover of program).
      • Program of Dedication of Memorial Window to Dr. Gunnison, May 2, 1919 (3 copies)
      • Several copies of the portrait of Dr. Gunnison (which hung in hall near EHHS room 104), including 8 x 10" glossy, 5 ½ x 7" matte, and 2 ½ x 3 ½" half-tone cut from Chronicles.
      • Three other half-tone photos of Dr. Gunnison removed from various publications
      • Testimonial dinner to Dr. Gunnison, held at the Hanover Club, Brooklyn, Dec. 29, 1896.
  - Gunnison Family
    - [Publications about Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison and his children], 1910, 1917, 1924 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Walter Balfour Gunnison (folder 2))
      Three limited edition publications about Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison and his children, including Walter Balfour Gunnison of EHHS. All three were published at Brooklyn, N.Y. by Herbert F. Gunnison.
      • An Autobiography of Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison... Prepared for Private Circulation Among their Children and Grandchildren. Second edition, 1910. No. 48 of 200 copies, signed "H. F. Gunnison." (Purchased Jan. 1972 by EHHS Library for $7.50 to complete the set.)
      • The Children of the Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison... Part Second of an Autobiography of the Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison. 1917. No. 194, presented to Dr. J. Herbert Low.
      • The Children of the Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison... Part Second... (Copy 2) No. 235, presented to Mr. Fred'k Huntington.
      • The Children of the Rev. Nathaniel Gunnison... Part Third... His Descendants in the World War. 1924. No. 60, presented to Dr. J. Herbert Low.
  - Hall, Mary E. (pioneer in school libraries)
    - [Correspondence, etc.], undated (Offsite-box RC-5a, Folder Kingsbury, Mary A.)
      Some correspondence from Miss Hall to Mary A. Kingsbury, with other information relating to Miss Hall.
  - Hamilton, Alexander
    - [Legal opinion], 1797 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Hamilton-Burr legal opinions)
      • Legal opinion, dated July 12, 1797, regarding the estate of Cornelius Van Duyn. Signed "A. Hamilton."
      • Contrary opinion, dated Sept. 28, 1797, held by "Col. Burr," in letter written by "R. Strong" to "Mr. John Terhune, Gravesend."
  - Harter, Eugene W. (EHHS teacher, 1896–1934), 1913–1939
    - "Galatea, A Fantastic Play.. .", 1913, undated (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder "Galatea" by Eugene W. Harter)
      • "Galatea, A Fantastic Play in Three Acts with Musical Interruptions; Founded on W. S. Gilbert's 'Pygmalion and Galatea' and furnished with Music and Lyrics" by Eugene W. Harter, n.d.
      • Clippings from Brooklyn Daily Eagle, June 5, 1913 and Oct. 1, 1913, about EHHS production of Galatea.
    - Obituary, 1934 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Eugene W. Harter)
    - "Dedication of Eugene W. Harter Memorial.. .", 1939 May 31 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Eugene W. Harter)
      "Dedication of Eugene W. Harter Memorial. Erasmus Hall Auditorium, Wednesday Evening, May 31st, 1939." (5 copies of program)
      The Harter Memorial is a mural depicting the wanderings of Odysseus, the Greek hero. It is located on the wall at the far end of the corridor where the EHHS offices (rooms 101–105) are located.
  - Hasbrouck, Jared (Erasmus Hall Academy principal, 1874–1879)
    - [Photograph of Hasbrouck with students], 1877, 1954 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Principals of Erasmus Hall Academy (Before 1896))
      5 x 7" photograph of Jared Hasbrouck on the steps of the Academy with the students, who are standing at attention with bayonets. Date, Nov. 1877. Gift of Milton B. Plotz, M.D., whose covering letter, dated Nov. 12, 1954, gives a history of the photo.
  - Holmes Medals
    - [Clippings listing winners], 1920s (Offsite-box RC-3a, Envelope Notebooks listing winners of Turner Medals)
      Pasted in the notebooks for the Turner Medals (q.v.) are clippings listing winners of the Holmes Medals (presented by "Miss Holmes") for some years in the 1920s.
  - Hudson-Fulton Celebration
    - "Hudson-Fulton celebration at Erasmus Hall" [printed program], 1909 September 29 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder EHHS—Misc. Programs)
      Hudson-Fulton celebration at Erasmus Hall, Wednesday, September 29th, 1909... Printed program.
    - "Official Medal of the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission, issued through the New York State Education Department to the Colleges and Secondary Schools. 1909. Designed by Emil Fuchs." (Offsite-box RC-10a, Folder Hudson-Fulton Celebration)
      Two bronze medals, 4" diameter, set into a 7 x 12" wood plaque.
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (U.S. Supreme Court Justice)
    - [Letter to Dr. Gunnison], 1912 June 29 (Offsite-box RC-8b, Folder Scrapbook of the 125th Anniv. of EHHS, 1912)
      Typewritten letter signed "Charles E. Hughes" on U.S. Supreme Court stationery, but dated Camp Abenaki, Lake Placid, N.Y., June 29, 1912, declining the invitation of Dr. Gunnison, Principal of EHHS, to attend the 125th anniversary pageant. In Scrapbook of the 125th Anniversary of Erasmus Hall High School, mounted on p. 42.
  - Illuminated Manuscript
    - A leaf from the Book of Hours, France, 1325 (Offsite-box RC-5a, Folder Illuminated Manuscripts (caution—GLASS))
      Between glass in frame. Size of leaf, about 5 ½ x 7". Size of frame, about 9 ½ x 11 ½".
      "In memory of Josephine Carlton, Erasmus Hall teacher, 1923–1953, from her colleagues of the English Dept." (Presented June 1956)
    - A leaf from the Book of Hours, France, 1420 (Offsite-box RC-5a, Folder Illuminated Manuscripts (caution—GLASS))
      Between glass in a frame. Size of leaf, about 4 ½ x 4 ½". Size of frame, about 8 ½ x 9".
      "In memory of Martin E. Glynn, Erasmus Hall teacher, 1929–1951, from his colleagues of the English Dept." (Presented June 1956)
    - From a Latin manuscript of the 14th c., the work of Spanish Carthusian monks, containing the prayers of the mass, 1300s (Offsite-box RC-7)
      Presented by Miss Marjorie Weirich.
    - Parchment page from a big book that contained the church service, undated (Offsite-box RC-7)
      Size 14 x 20".
  - Ink Stands [NOT PRESENT]
    - Two stone ink stands, perhaps used in Erasmus Hall Academy, undated (Box [unknown])
      Two stone ink stands, perhaps used in Erasmus Hall Academy.
  - Israel, Saul (EHHS principal, 1965–1972)
    - "Installation of Mr. Saul Israel, Principal" [6 copies], 1965 October 27 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Saul Israel, principal, EHHS, 1965–1972)
  - Kellogg, Jonathan W. (Erasmus Hall Academy principal, 1823–1833)
    - "Erasmus Gets Portrait of Early Headmaster" [copy 1], Sunday News, 1955 November 13 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Principals of Erasmus Hall Academy (Before 1896))
      Clipping regarding gift to Erasmus Hall High School of portrait of Kellogg, presented by his great-granddaughter, Charlotte H. Meade. Includes photo of Dr. John F. McNeill with portrait of Kellogg.
    - "Erasmus Gets Portrait of Early Headmaster" [copy 2], Sunday News, 1955 November 13 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Dr. John F. McNeill)
  - Kemfax
    - "Kemfax," published by the Physical Science Department of Erasmus Hall High School, vol. 1, no. 1, 1962 Spring (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Science Publications including Biota)
  - Kingsbury, Mary A. (EHHS librarian, 1900–1931)
    - [Letters, photographs, clippings], undated (Offsite-box RC-5a, Folder Kingsbury, Mary A.)
      Miss Kingsbury was the first professionally trained public school librarian in the United States. Letters written by Miss Kingsbury about her years at Erasmus Hall, letters written by Mary E. Hall (another pioneer in the movement for professional school librarians), and photographs, clippings, etc., about Miss Kingsbury.
  - Kopy Kat
    - "Kopy Kat," issued by class 6623 (during principalship of J. F. McNeill; Charlotte Crawford, adviser), undated (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Folder: EHHS—Misc. Programs)
      • Vol. 1, no. 1 (March 8, ----)
      • Vol. 1, no. 2 (March 25, ----)
      Includes amusing "Words That Made Some Teachers Famous," e.g., Miss Mastin: "The more I see of some people, the more I like my dog."
  - Lantern
    - "The Lantern," issued by the Poetry Club of Erasmus Hall High School, 1934, 1936, undated (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder "The Lantern")
      • Vol. 1, no. 3 (Nov. 13, 1934) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 1, no. 4 (Nov. 20, 1934) [2 copies]
      • Spring issue, 1936
      • Autumn issue, n.d.
  - Lawrence, Thomas Gordon (EHHS Biology Department chairman)
    - "Erasmus Hall High School Biology Department Luncheon in Honor of Thomas Gordon Lawrence, Summer Magister Scientiae", 1967 June 10 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder EHHS Faculty Dinners #2)
      Program and special "Regents" exam prepared for the event.
  - Lefferts family
    - Last will and testament of Lefferts Pieterse, progenitor of the Lefferts family in America, 1702 August 30 (Offsite-box RC-6b, Folder Lefferts Family)
      Dated Aug. 30, 1702, this two-page manuscript is signed by Pieterse and witnessed by three of his Flatbush contemporaries: Pieter Stryker, Andriese Janse, and Henry Filkin.
    - Last will and testament of Lefferts Pieterse, progenitor of the Lefferts family in America [photostats], [1702 August 30] (Offsite-box RC-6b, Tube Photostats of the unrecorded will of Leffert Pieterse)
    - Bergen, Teunis G. Genealogy of the Lefferts family... (Albany: Munsell), 1878 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Bergen. Lefferts Genealogy, 1878)
  - Literary and Philosophical Association of Flatbush
    - Constitution and minutes of the Literary and Philosophical Association of Flatbush, 1836–1838 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Minutes of the Literary & Philosophical Association of Flatbush, 1836–1838)
      6 ½ x 8" notebook with marbled covers containing the constitution and minutes of the Literary and Philosophical Association of Flatbush. The minutes run from May 1836 to Feb. 1838.
      This was an adult organization, and [at] each meeting a member would give a discourse on some assigned topic. Dr. John B. Zabriskie was an active member of this Literary Association, and mention of it appears in Historical Sketch of the Zabriskie Homestead by P. L. Schenck (1881), p. 55–56. Why these minutes cease in 1838 is a puzzle, since the Association was still active during the winter of 1841–1842, at which time Dr. Thomas M. Strong delivered the series of lectures that was later published as the first history of Flatbush (1842). These minutes were written by Dr. John B. Zabriskie (comparison made with letter on file in Zabriskie Papers, Box 2).
  - Livingston, John H. (Erasmus Hall Academy principal, 1787–1792)
    - De Witt, John. The path of the just as the shining light: a funeral discourse pronounced in the Reformed Dutch Church of New-Brunswick occasioned by the decease of the Rev. John H. Livingston, D.D.S.T.P. (New-Brunswick: William Meyer), 1825 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Rev. Dr. John H. Livingston)
      39 p.
    - [Letter and engraving], 1813 October 2 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Rev. Dr. John H. Livingston)
      Original one-page holograph letter to "Reverend Mr. Peter Lowe, Flat-Bush, Long Island, New York," written from "N. Brunswick, Oct. 2, 1813" by the Rev. John H. Livingston, D.D. Signed simply "J. H. Livingston."
      His purpose in writing to Rev. Lowe, who at that time was Principal of the Academy, was to secure a teaching position for a friend's son. (If we may judge by the list of teachers in the Chronicles, young Isaac S. Brouwer did not receive an appointment.) This letter has added significance because Rev. Lowe endorsed this letter in his own hand: "Rev. Doct. Livingston, Oct. 2, 1813, P. L."
      Accompanied by engraving of Dr. Livingston which was probably removed from a copy of Gunn's Memoirs of Dr. Livingston (of which EHHS Library has three copies).
      According to notation on manila folder, this letter was a gift of Dr. Charles Lauriston Livingston Jr., May 12, 1952.
    - Diploma granted to Jacob Wyckoff, 1816 October (Offsite-box RC-10a, Frame Jacob Wyckoff diploma)
      Diploma granted to Jacob Wyckoff, apparently from the New Brunswick (New Jersey) college. Dr. Livingston signed as president of the college. Dated October 1816. Vellum, framed, under glass, 12 x 12".
    - Gunn, Alexander. Memoirs of the Rev. John H. Livingston... (New York: William A. Mercein), 1829, 1856 (Offsite-box RC-11, Folder Gunn. Memoirs of Rev. John H. Livingston)
      Two editions (1829, 1856).
    - Livingston, John H. The psalms and hymns, with the catechism, confession of faith, and liturgy of the Reformed Dutch Church in North America (New Brunswick: Deare & Terhune), 1814 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Psalms and Hymns of the Reformed Dutch Church)
      This copy owned by Dr. John B. Zabriskie (1805–1848) of Flatbush, with his signature on fly-leaf. Bookplate of his grandson, John B. Zabriskie.
  - Lloyd Family
    - Rowe, Elizabeth. Devout Exercises of the Heart... (New York: William Durrell), 1795 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Lloyd Family of Flatbush—Books)
      Book that belonged to Abigail (Lefferts) Lloyd (1759–1847), daughter of Jacob Leffers and wife of Capt. Bateman Lloyd, of Flatbush. Inscribed on fly-leaf: "A. L. Lloyd to C. L. Duryea, Flatbush, 1842."
      With a delicate paper cutting by Mrs. Lloyd affixed inside the front cover (see P. L. Schenck, The Zabriskie Homestead, 1881, for details of her artistry).
    - Holcroft, Thomas. Life of Baron Frederick Trenck (N.Y.: William Durrell), 1796, 1797 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Lloyd Family of Flatbush—Books)
      Book that belonged to a member of the Lloyd family of Flatbush. Inscribed on fly-leaf: "Lydia Lloyd[']s Book, October 2nd 1797." With bookplate of John B. Zabriskie.
  - Lock [NOT PRESENT]
    - Old lock from the front door to Erasmus Hall Academy., undated (Box [unknown])
  - Long Island—History
    - [Two histories of Long Island], 1828, 1843 (Offsite-box RC-17, Folder Wood, Silas | Thompson)
      • Thompson, Benjamin F. History of Long Island... New York, 1843. 2 vols.
      • Wood, Silas. Sketch of the first settlement of the several towns on Long Island... A new edition. Brooklyn: Spooner, 1828.
  - Long Island Star
    - Long Island Star, 1821 November 1–December 27 (Offsite-box RC-7, Folder The Long Island Star)
      Publ. by Alden Spooner, Fulton Street, Brooklyn. Issued weekly.
      Page 4, col. 4 of each issue has advt. for Erasmus Hall Academy, with list of tuition charges ("Board in the family of the Principal [washing included] $50") and references.
      The issue of Nov. 8 (p. 3, col. 5) has report of meeting of Kings Co. Agricultural Society, held at the Court-house in Flatbush, Jeremiah Lott, Sec'y.
  - Lott, Abraham
    - Meijers, L. Woordenschat Verdeelt in 1. Bastaardt-Woorden. 2. Konst-Woorden. 3. Verouderde Woorden (t'Amsteldam: Jeronimus Ratelband), 1745, 1762 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Book (1745) with bookplate of Abraham Lott)
      Book that belonged to Abraham Lott of Flatbush, with the engraved bookplate of "Abraham Lott" showing the family coat of arms. Signed on title page, "Abrm Lott junr 1762." The bookplate may be that of the senior Abraham Lott (1684–1754).
  - Lott, Engelbert (d. 1779)
    - [Signature of Engelbert Lott], 1778 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      The signature of Engelbert Lott, grandfather of Jeremiah Lott (q.v.) appears at the end of the inventory of the estate of John R. Cowenhoven (q.v.), 1778. Also present is the signature of Engelbert Lott Jr.
  - Lott, Jeremiah (1776–1861)
    - "Governor Clinton requests the Honor of Mr. Lott's Company at Dinner, on Thursday the 17th Janry. at 4 o'Clock", 1822 January 10 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)